# **Andreas Harison Manurung**

Contact | andreasmanro@gmail.com | +62 852 8754 1348 Serang, Banten

#### Summary

Skilled at chemical analysis especially environment chemistry and microbiology analysis and studied at research renewable energy and activated charcoal. I am a self-motivated, rapid learner, strong analytical. Work well as a team member as well as independently. Have operated Chemical instrument such as AAS, ICP-OES, Spectrometry UV-VIS, Turbidity meter.

#### **Education**

#### **INSTITUT PERTANIAN BOGOR**

August 2012 – February 2017

Bachelor of Chemistry | GPA: 3.36/4.00

• Undergraduate Thesis: Membrane Electrode Assembly Composite Polysulfone Sulfonated – Titanium Dioxide for Methanol Fuel Cell Application

## **Professional Experiences**

PT SWING INDONESIA Serang, Banten

Quality Control Supervisor

December 2021 – Now

- Led various projects such as STP, WTP, WWTP; Activated Carbon and provided support to complete them.
- Supervise 5 people and responsible research to improve Laboratory SOP such as JIS testing method, JWWA testing method, HACH testing method and research to make a product.

#### FOREST PRODUCTS RESEARCH AND DEVELOPMENT CENTER

Bogor, West Java

Student Laboratory Internship

June 2016 – August 2016

 Studied about Analysis of activated charcoal Acacia Mangium bark as a byproduct of the manufacture of methanol using hydrothermal system.

PT FRISIAN FLAG Jakarta, DKI Jakarta

Student Laboratory Internship

June 2015 - August 2015

• Studied about Analysis of calcium levels in the basic ingredients of infant milk powder using Inductively Coupled Plasma Optical Emission Spectrometry (ICP-OES) Methods.

## **INSTITUT PERTANIAN BOGOR**

Bogor, West Java

Professor Assistant

June 2014 – July 2016

# **Organizational Experiences**

#### **BADAN EKSEKUTIF MAHASISWA FMIPA IPB**

Bogor, West Java

Head of Literature Division

June 2020 - May 2021

• Led 5 divisions members in handling the organization literature

#### **IKATAN MAHASISWA KIMIA IPB**

June 2013 - February 2017

## **Additional Information**

Language Indonesian (Native) and English (Upper-Intermediate)

Computer Skills Expertise in Microsoft Office: Ms Excel, Word, Powerpoint; Design Software: Coreldraw, Photoshop;

Chemisist Software: Chembio hyperchem and draw.

Chemist Skills Metal Analysis, Food Analysis, Microbiology Analysis, Spectrophotometer analysis (AAS, ICP, UV-VIS, etc),

Wastewater Analysis

Certificates Training HACCP & ISO 9001:2015, Training Go Green Bioplastic and Fuel Cell, Training IPB & Kyoto University

International Symposium Global Environment, ESQ Leadership Training, Journalistic Training Metro